DataFinOps connects real requirements to pricing, entitlement, governance, and reproducible savings evidence.
The sandbox verifies network, program, pricing, subscription, and API entitlement. The wallet remains a public reference only.
Aggregate usage maps to products, while unallocated spend stays visible. Hard requirements remain separate from preferences.
Every input is frozen. A deterministic optimizer proposes valid configurations, and an independent verifier checks every hard constraint.
Adding a hard fixture creates a new snapshot and recommendation. The requirement is never silently relaxed, and prior evidence remains replayable.
Procurement and finance approve the exact proposal hash under separate roles. Material change invalidates approval.
The unsigned summary binds network, program, changes, amount, expiry, and hashes. The client-side demo signer uses no private-key input or funded transaction.
Confirmation, activation, and effective entitlement are verified separately. Duplicate callbacks never create a second purchase.
Only a complete, verified period can label the synthetic delta realized. Corrections append reversals without rewriting history.
Optimize cost, preserve coverage, and verify value. That is DataFinOps.